Michael Morin

Database Administrator

Bellingham, WA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Michael-Morin/10aa8a4dd98b7022

DBA and Business Intelligence, experienced in information systems integration, data analysis, and project leadership. Proficient in database modeling, development, performance tuning, and system architecture. Strong analysis, critical thinking, and communications skills with customer focus. Accomplished at process optimization and automation. Able to work independently, or as a member of a team. Infectious enthusiasm with insatiable intellectual curiosity.

Core Excellencies

- SQL Server
- Reporting Services (SSRS)
- Analysis Services (SSAS)
- Integration Services (SSIS)
- Business Intelligence Development Studio (BIDS)
- Management Studio (SSMS)
- Data Mining
- System Architecture / Infrastructure design
- Optimization / Performance Tuning
- Automation
- Team partner and independent worker
- Project leadership
- Data modeling and analysis
- Critical Thinking
- Communication
- Creativity
- Persistence
- Integrity

WORK EXPERIENCE

Database Administrator

Department of Defense DIACAP - January 2014 to July 2016

Production and development DBA role. Implemented disaster recovery solution and failover process utilizing log shipping. Positioned SQL Servers for Department of Defense DIACAP security certification. Performed bulk data modifications. Lead deployments to live site. Refactored processes resulting in improved revenue, performance and targeted development. Provided analysis on reporting and platform architecture.

Data Warehouse Lead

Homax Products - March 2010 to October 2013

Developed data warehouse in ERP environment (JDE) encompassing data marts and cubes for Sales, Financial, POS, Social Media, and Customer Care operations and analysis, drawing from multiple systems and sources. Built reporting solutions utilizing Reporting Services, Analysis Services, Excel, and LogiXML. Designed SAN system.

Business Intelligence Consultant / Database Analyst

- February 2007 to March 2010

contracts at Microsoft and Xbox)

Developed reports, dashboards, and scorecards in Reporting Services (SSRS), Analysis Services (SSAS) and Excel in a very large data warehouse environment. Streamlined existing reporting and business processes through innovative approaches. Provided deep-dive analysis into new XBox initiatives and marketing.

American Management Services

Pinnacle Realty - April 2004 to February 2007

Business Systems Analyst / DBA Lead

Production and development DBA role encompassing query and database optimization, system tuning, upgrades, and monitoring. Integrate multiple mission critical business systems including Accounting, Payroll, Asset Management and Human Resources. Develop data warehouse providing cross-department analysis. Lead rollout of Kronos implementation.

Sr. Database Analyst

Northwest Center - March 2001 to March 2004

Maintained and upgraded company databases, overseeing migration from MS Access to SQL Server. Streamlined business processes. Performance analysis of marketing efforts. Supervise analyst team.

DBA / Web Systems Administrator

Webforia.com - June 2000 to November 2000

Directed rollouts of major web platform revisions, including testing and scheduling. Analyzed site traffic and performance. Defined hardware specifications for database servers.

Network Engineering Consultant

Massachusetts Department of Education - November 1997 to July 1999

Planned and executed strategy for migration of 500-seat environment from Novell to Microsoft. Developed intranet internal IT resources and reporting solution monitoring web site statistics. Provided training and direction for internal personnel.

Senior Network Engineer

Net Daemons Associates - Woburn, MA - June 1997 to October 1997

Created training and foundation structures for new Microsoft Technologies department. Provided project management and design services.

Network Engineer / Trainer

Valinor - Waltham, MA - June 1996 to June 1997

Automated classroom setup, published in MS Technet. Provided training in Windows-based networking with consistently excellent evaluations. Provided installation and administration services.

Data Analyst / Programmer

Oxxford Information Technology, Inc - Hagaman, NY - January 1995 to June 1996

Managed and developed customer databases. Developed pattern matching and artificial intelligence ETL routines. Published custom market analyses.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science